Before we start coding our content provider, let's
make sure the manifest is set up correctly.
You need to update the androidmanifest.xml file within
the application tag to add the content provider. So
that android's content resolver can see it. The
authority really should match your package name. While
the name indicates which file your content provider
class is in. Next, let's code up on create.
We'll begin by creating an instance variable for our
database helper. In on create, we initiate our instance variable.
We return true, which is how we tell Android that
the content provider has been created successfully. It turns out
that we can repurpose the same test we did
for the database to test our new content provider. This
will allow you to both test your content provider code
and see how the content provider calls replace the SQLI
database calls. Let's start by using Android
Studio to copy TestDB to test provider.
Let's rename test create DB, to test delete DB.
So we can start with a clean slate. We'll just leave the M context dot delete
database line in there. We'll leave the other
test the same, we'll get to it soon.